# **Clement Fung**

Email: <u>clement.y.fung@gmail.com</u> Website: <u>https://clementfung.github.io/</u>

#### **SUMMARY**

My current research interests include the security and privacy of distributed systems. Most notably, I am interested in distributed multi-party machine learning and corresponding attacks and defenses on these system. Lately, I am especially interested in the security and privacy issues surrounding Google's federated learning.

## **PUBLICATIONS**

## Refereed publications

• Brokered Agreements in Multi-Party Machine Learning

Clement Fung, Ivan Beschastnikh.

To appear at the 10th ACM SIGOPS Asia-Pacific Workshop on Systems (APSys 2019) Hangzhou, China, August 2019.

• GainForest: Scaling Climate Finance for Forest Conservation using Interpretable Machine Learning on Satellite Imagery

David Dao, Catherine Cang, Clement Fung, Ming Zhang, Nick Pawlowski, Reuven Gonzales, Nick Beglinger, Ce Zhang.

Climate Change: How Can AI Help?: ICML 2019 Workshop

Long Beach, CA, June 2019.

#### Non-refereed publications

- Biscotti: A Ledger for Private and Secure Peer-to-Peer Machine Learning. Muhammad Shayan, Clement Fung, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh. *arXiv* November 2018.
- Dancing in the Dark: Private Multi-Party Machine Learning in an Untrusted Setting.

  Clement Fung, Jamie Koerner, Stewart Grant, Ivan Beschastnikh.

  arXiv November 2018.
- Mitigating Sybils in Federated Learning Poisoning.

  Clement Fung, Chris J.M. Yoon, Ivan Beschastnikh. arXiv August 2018.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### PhD, Societal Computing

August 2019 - present

Carnegie Mellon University, Pittsburgh, PA

#### Research:

• Starting as a member of CyLab in August of 2019.

#### MSc, Computer Science

2016 - 2018

University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC Cumulative GPA: 88 / 100

Thesis:

• Dancing in the Dark: Private Multi-Party Machine Learning in an Untrusted Setting. Supervisor: Ivan Beschastnikh

#### Achievements:

- UBC CS Department Graduate Teaching Assistant Award, 2017
- UBC CS Department Student Service Award, 2017

# Research Projects:

- Biscotti: A secure, private blockchain-based system for multi-party machine learning
- FoolsGold: A sybil-resilient federated learning protocol against model poisoning
- TorMentor: A system for distributed, collaborative, anonymous machine learning
- InsuLearn: A system for distributed learning on private medical data
- DistributedClocks: A library for vector clock instrumentation of distributed systems

#### **Graduate Courses:**

- CPSC 532R Graphical Models (*Prof. Siamak Ravanbakhsh*)
- CPSC 540 Advanced Machine Learning (Prof. Mark Schmidt)
- CPSC 538W Data At Scale (Prof. Andrew Warfield)
- CPSC 538B Distributed Systems (*Prof. Ivan Beschastnikh*)
- CPSC 536F Algorithmic Game Theory (*Prof. Hu Fu*)
- CPSC 340 Machine Learning (*Prof. Mark Schmidt*)

# BASc, Honours Systems Design Engineering, Dean's Honour's List Distinction 2011 - 2016 University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON

Cumulative GPA: 88 / 100

# Capstone Project:

• Driven: A Automated System for Intelligent Annotation and Analysis of Lane Change Sentiment Supervisor: Alexander Wong

#### Awards:

- Sanford Fleming Award for Co-operative Proficiency, 2016
- GM Canada Innovation Award, 2016 \$500
- W.W. King Exchange Fellowship, 2015 \$500
- President's International Experience Award, 2014 \$1500
- Sanford Fleming Award for Outstanding Communication in Work Term Report, 2013 \$300
- Colonel Hugh Heasley Engineering Scholarship, 2011 \$10000
- University of Waterloo President's Scholarship of Distinction, 2011 \$2000

## Achievements:

- Dean's Honour's List, Winter 2016
- Dean's Honour's List, Winter 2013 Ranked 2nd / 81 students
- Dean's Honour's List, Spring 2012 Ranked 2nd / 85 students
- Dean's Honour's List, Fall 2011 Ranked 3rd / 94 students

## TEACHING EXPERIENCE

**Teaching Assistant** 

Sept 2016 - Dec 2018

University of British Columbia

• DSCI 571: Supervised Learning

Fall 2018

Instructors: Mikchael Gelbart, Varada Kolhatkar

• DSCI 523: Data Wrangling

Fall 2018

Instructors: Jenny Bryan, Rodolfo Lourenzutti

• CPSC 340: Machine Learning Instructor: Michael Gelbart

Winter 2018

• CPSC 340: Machine Learning

Fall 2017

Instructor: Mark Schmidt

• CPSC 210: Software Construction

Winter 2017

Instructors: Norman Hutchinson, Paul Carter, Mehrdad Oveisi

• CPSC 210: Software Construction

Fall 2016

Instructors: Norman Hutchinson, Ryan Vogt, Jonatan Schroeder

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

**Software Engineer** 

January 2019 - July 2019

Oasis Labs, Berkeley, CA, USA

• Applications for secure data sharing and other confidential protocols in an early stage blockchain

Research Assistant

January 2017 - December 2018

University of British Columbia, Vancouver, BC, Canada

• Research on security of machine learning in the Networks, Systems and Security (NSS) Lab.

**Software Engineering Intern** 

June - August 2015

LinkedIn Corporation, Sunnyvale, CA, USA

• Analytics: Building infrastructure for online relevance scoring at scale

**Software Engineering Intern** 

September 2014 - December 2014

LinkedIn Corporation, Mountain View, CA, USA

• Distributed Data Systems: Prototyped and designed new derived data serving system, Venice

**Software Engineering Intern** 

January 2014 - April 2014

Voicebox Technologies, Bellevue, WA, USA

Server and Tools: Implemented layer for concurrent database access on a mobile service

**Software Developer** 

May 2013 - August 2013

Ontario Institute for Cancer Research, Toronto, ON

• Software developer in Paul Boutros' bioinformatics research group

**Software Developer** 

September 2012 - December 2012

pVelocity, Toronto, ON

**QA** Analyst

January 2012 - April 2012

pVelocity, Toronto, ON